Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/rijad-saric (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Engineering

Research

Problem Solving

Languages

English (Full Professional)

German (Limited Working)

Bosnian/Croatian/Serbian (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Find Your Spark

IHP - Autonomous Driving Summer School

IPAP Certificate of Participation

Natural Language Processing Course

IEEE SYPC Certificate of Attendance 2016 - 2018

Publications

Compensated PID Regulation of Ambient Temperature using New Approach to the System Identification Based on Forced Oscillations

Rijad Saric

Embedded System Engineer | Data Scientist | Researcher and Innovator

Summary

A graduated embedded system engineer with significant experience in various fields of computer and electrical engineering. During my career, I have gained experience in both industry and teaching and I would like to continue my future path by contributing to various innovative research projects and assignments. Also, I have developed strong leadership skills, fast learning and adjusting abilities including planning, analysis, design, problem-solving, maintenance and implementation of projects.

Experience

La Trobe Innovation & Entrepreneurship Foundry (LIEF) Research And Development Engineer October 2017 - Present

Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina, Melbourne, Australia

LIEF represents an innovative engineering lab located in Melbourne (AU) including offices in Sarajevo and Tuzla (BH). The primary mission is to provide modern solutions and products that will have a positive impact on society and World as well. A team of qualified engineers is responsible for researching, prototyping, developing and modelling final products and services.

As an R&D engineer, I am mostly involved in embedded engineering projects that require real-time OS functionalities and adequate hardware description. Moreover, I am also working on a 3D reconstruction project that needs a strong background in computer vision and image processing.

Bosnia & Herzegovina Futures Foundation Scholar & Volunteer October 2017 - Present Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina

The BH Futures Foundation was founded at the end of 2015 to support the youth of Bosnia and Herzegovina through the power of quality education and technology access. The global goal is to offer financial and career support

through a large number of scholarships as well as internships in BH and abroad.

I am a holder of BHFF excellence academic scholarship in 2018. As a BHFF volunteer, I devoted my free time to promote BHFF through various presentations, workshops, academies, and conferences.

IHP

Embedded Systems Engineer - Research Internship March 2019 - May 2019 (3 months)

Frankfurt (Oder), Germany

Sarajevo School of Science and Technology Teaching Assistant October 2016 - December 2018 (2 years 3 months)

Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina

I was a teaching assistant for electrical and electronics engineering courses such as fundamentals of EE, analogues electronic, digital integrated circuits and electrical measurements conducted in the laboratory conditions. Most of the stated courses included exercises/simulations in MATLAB and Simulink.

Also, I was tutoring introduction to programming using C/C++, assembly language programming, computer organization including the logic (gate-level) design.

CoderDojo

Teacher

August 2018 - August 2018 (1 month)

Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina

I was teaching fundamentals of C/C++ programming during the summer coding school named CoderDojo intended to high-school students organized by Bit Alliance BH. The primary objective of Bit Alliance is to adjust curriculums of all educational institutions in BH based on the current needs of the IT industry.

BH Telecom

Software Engineer Internship

July 2016 - December 2016 (6 months)

Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina

Responsible for creating a functional location of the newly installed equipment using SAP ERP software. Furthermore, I analysed customer requests

Page 2 of 3

regarding technical problems using Remedy application. I gained experience in telecommunication network management, packet inspection, traffic analysis, and performance characterization. My role allowed me to cooperate with the team who worked in day-to-day operational activities including occasional first-level diagnostic support and scheduling upgrades.

Munich Startup
Participant
July 2015 - July 2015 (1 month)
Munich, Germany

I had an opportunity to visit the Technical University of Munich (TUM) and participate in the Munich Startup week. As a part of the international development team, I was involved in building a web and mobile app named "ParkingON". The created app is designed to help a user in finding the nearest free parking lot in the city area.

Education

International BURCH University

Master of Electrical and Electronics Engineering , Embedded

Systems · (2018 - 2019)

Sarajevo School of Science and Technology

Bachelor of Science (Hons), Computer Science | Electrical and Electronics

Engineering (2013 - 2017)

University of Buckingham

Bachelor of Science with Honours, Computer Science · (2013 - 2017)